# **Nguyen Trong Ruong**

Software Developer

Address: Cat Que, Hoai Duc, Ha Noi Phone number: 0972074537 Email: trongruong99@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/ruong32 LeetCode: https://leetcode.com/ruong32

## **About**

By far, I am a 3-year-experience programmer with good English skills. Throughout the course of my professional journey, I have worked as Frontend developer with solid knowledge about JavaScript, HTML, CSS and amazing powerful frontend library, which is React. Furthermore, I also have been employed as Backend developer with certain knowledge about frameworks (Spring Boot, Express), databases (MySQL, MongoDB) and REST API design.

## Education

University of Engineering & Technology (VNU-UET)

Faculty of Information Technology

From 08/2017 to 06/2022 Graduate time: 06/2022

# **Experience**

## 10/2022 - Present

# Frontend developer

Coc Coc, 8th floor, ICON4 building, No.243A, La Thanh street, Dong Da, Ha Noi

- Maintaining Savior extention which allows users to download videos on Coc Coc browser. Mainly using Javascript.
- Maintaining Newtab a startup page which is shown when users open a new tab on Coc Coc browser. Mainly using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Developing Quizz web site using React and Next.js.
- Maintaining Referral web site using React and Next.js.

# 05/2021 - 09/2022 Full Stack developer

Alo, No.69, Vu Trong Phung street, Thanh Xuan Trung, Thanh Xuan, Ha Noi

- Developing REST APIs for Alo app and Alo web admin to manage data using Vert.x with MySQL database.
- Developing UI for admin web using React.
- Developing UI for client web using Next.js and React.
- · Developing an MVC web for Customer Service using MySQL for database, SpringBoot for backend and Thymeleaf for frontend.
- Deploying frontend, backend to server and setting up environment for testing.

# 06/2020 - 04/2021

# **Backend developer**

Viettel Solution, No 1, Tran Huu Duc street, My Dinh, Tu Liem, Ha Noi

- Developing backend for web application using Spring Boot framework and frontend using
- Using Docker to deploy applications.

# **Technical skill**

Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS Programming language

Framework/Library Spring Boot, Express, React Native, Angular, React, Next.js, Vert.x

> MySQL, MongoDB Database

Git, Docker, IntelliJ, Visual Studio Code, Terminal

# **Project**

# Persional project

#### • 8/2023 - Present: Grammar Check

Technologies: React, NextJS, Tailwind.

**Team size:** 1 members.

Description: A page to help users improve their English writing by giving better sentences

but keeping main idea. **Position:** Frontend developer.

#### Responsibilities:

• Developing text areas to type input and display result with copy and delete buttons.

- Highlighting respective sentences in two text areas.
- Developing popup to show synonyms in result area and replace original word by one of the synonyms.
- Developing zoom feature without zooming entire browser.

#### • 7/2022 - 8/2022: Passo

**Technologies:** React, NextJS.

**Team size:** 1 members.

**Description:** A landing page to introduce business and their products (banners, design templates). It is also a media to connect to potential customers.

Position: Fullstack developer.

#### Responsibilities:

- o Developing pages bases on given design.
- Supportint responsive.
- Building a simple backend service to send email.
- Deploying to hosting service.
- Installing SSL certificate.

#### **Business project**

#### • 10/2022 - 9/2023: Coc Coc - Referral

Technologies: React, NextJS, SASS.

**Team size:** 3 members.

**Description:** Coc Coc's content web page where users can track their sharing Coc Coc campaigns and their commission.

**Position:** Frontend developer.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Updating new UI in user information, payment method, commission history, withdraw history tab.
- o Maintaining.

# • 10/2022 - 9/2023: Coc Coc - Quizz

Technologies: React, NextJS, Tailwind.

**Team size:** 3 members.

**Description:** Coc Coc's content web page where users can play quizzes.

**Position:** Frontend developer.

# **Responsibilities:**

- Developing category screen, detail quiz screen and playing quiz screen.
- Implementing share quiz's result to Facebook feature.
- Supporting old browsers.
- · Maintaining.

# • 10/2022 - 9/2023: Coc Coc - Newtab

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Stylus, Webpack, JavaScript.

**Team size:** 3 members.

**Description:** Coc Coc's web page appeared when user open new tab on Coc Coc browser.

**Position:** Frontend developer.

# Responsibilities:

- Implementing new account popup.
- Implementing new setting panel and widgets UI.
- Maintaining.

# • 10/2022 - 9/2023: Coc Coc - Savior

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Stylus, Webpack, JavaScript.

**Team size:** 3 members.

**Description:** Coc Coc's extension that helps users download videos on Coc Coc browser.

**Position:** Frontend developer.

#### Responsibilities:

• Implementing downloading videos on TikTok without watermark feature.

• Maintaining, usually when target websites changed their domain or web structure.

#### • 6/2021 - 10/2022: Alo

Technologies: Vert.x, Mysql, React, Next.js.

**Team size:** 8 members.

**Description:** A mobile application has a mission that brings to people high quality services.

**Position:** Fullstack developer.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Building APIs which allow users to be able to interact (booking, contacting to service providers,...) with the system and assist administrators to manage the system.
- Building a website for administrators and a website for SEO.

#### • 11/2020 - 4/2021: Intelligent Video Analysis

Technologies: Spring Boot, Angular, MariaDB, Jenkins, SonarQube, Kubernetes.

**Team size:** 6 members.

**Description:** A client page for users to demonstrate AI features such as face recognizing, face comparing,... and these features' document.

Position: Fullstack developer.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Building APIs allowing the admin to manage AI document and service to store files.
  Using Eureka and Spring Cloud Gateway to implement microservice architecture and Docker to deploy applications.
- Building a page to display document, a page header with dynamic items and a drag drop image component. Integrating backend's API with frontend.
- Using Jenkins, Gitlab for CICD.

## • 6/2020 - 10/2020: Viettel Open Digital Platform

Technologies: Spring Boot, Angular, MariaDB, Jenkins, SonarQube, Kubernetes.

**Team size:** 6 members.

**Description:** An admin page for managing products in eShop (another system of Viettel). Its main function is synchronizing products between BCCS and eShop in multiple languages.

Position: Backend developer.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Building APIs allowing admin to manage catalogs and products which can be shown or not on eShop.
- Providing APIs which eShop can get catalogs and products from.

# **Educational project**

#### • 2/2020 - 6/2020: TOEIC Test (Developing mobile application)

Technologies: JavaScript, React Native, SQLite.

**Team size:** 2 members.

**Description:** An application helping users prepare for TOEIC exam by providing sample tests. Otherwise it also helps users learn English by using tags which contain pictures, meaning, and pronunciation of English words.

Position: Mobile developer.

# Responsibilities:

- Coding learning screens which contain tags, favorite word and reminder function.
- Implementing dark mode.

## • 2/2020 - 6/2020: FHQ Music (User interface design)

Technologies: JavaScript, React Native, SQLite.

**Team size:** 2 members.

**Description:** A music application streaming audio online. Main functions: streaming music, mini player, playlist, adding songs to list, favorite songs, listening history, searching songs.

**Position:** Mobile developer.

### Responsibilities:

- Designing home page.
- Handling streaming audio on player and minimizing it to mini player.
- Coding adding song, favorite song, listening history function.

#### • 8/2019 - 12/2019: **Web Chat** (Developing web application)

Technologies: JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, EJS, Socket.IO, MongoDB.

**Team size:** 4 members.

**Description:** A real-time chat application providing abilities to login with Facebook and Google, verify email, add friends, real-time chat with friends, create group chat, emoji, share images and videos.

Position: Backend developer.

Responsibilities:

• Handling real-time chat, group chat, sharing media functions.

• Developing UI for chat page.

• 8/2018 - 12/2018: Dictionary (Oriented Object Programming)

Technologies: Java, Java Swing.

**Team size:** 2 members.

Description: A simple dictionary for PC can translate from Vietnamese word to English

word. Supporting English pronunciation.

**Position:** Developer. **Responsibilities:** 

• Building UI using Java Swing.

• Combining UI and logic.

# Certificate

TOEIC

770

22/03/2021 - 22/03/2023